

□ (+1) 202-222-8529 | ■ natalieahn@gmail.com | 🌴 natalieahn.github.io | 🖸 natalieahn | 🛅 natalieahn

Summary_

Data scientist focused on machine learning, natural language processing, and statistical analysis. 5+ years experience in news media and foreign policy, prior to academic research. Interested in opportunities in industry to develop computational, data-driven solutions to societal challenges.

Education

| 2018 | Ph.D. in Public Policy (expected), University of California - Berkeley, Goldman School of Public Policy | Berkeley, CA |
|------|---|----------------|
| 2006 | M.A. in Strategic Studies and International Economics, Johns Hopkins University, SAIS | Washington, DC |
| 2004 | B.A. in International Relations (Minor in Computer Science), Stanford University | Stanford, CA |

Academic Experience _____

Goldman School of Public Policy (GSPP), UC Berkeley

Berkelev, CA

Ph.D. Candidate, Independent Research

2012 - Present

- · Developed open source software tools in Python for data processing and analysis, including for Spanish text morphological analysis, Wikipedia search and entity labeling, person name and document matching, and statistical model sampling and visualization (available on Github).
- Extensive data collection, processing, measurement, and analysis of political institutions and events. Developed NLP/ML ensemble approach to classifying government documents, as well as unsupervised approach to information extraction with multi-task learning in Tensorflow.

PROJECT SUPERVISOR, UNDERGRADUATE RESEARCH APPRENTICE PROGRAM

2016 - 2017

• Supervised research assistants collecting and coding data on political leaders. Mentorship in research methods, including data analysis in R.

GRADUATE STUDENT RESEARCHER, INSTITUTE FOR RESEARCH ON LABOR AND EMPLOYMENT

 Administered several national surveys of local politicians. Collected and coded national sample of municipal financial records via FOIA requests. Coded legislative histories of pension governance and actuarial policies. Processed and analyzed U.S. population and local govt census data.

D-Lab (Data Lab), UC Berkeley

Berkeley, CA

Workshop Instructor: Programming Fundamentals, Python Fundamentals, NLP with NLTK, Intro to Regex

2016 - 2017

International and Area Studies Program, UC Berkeley

Berkeley, CA

Graduate Student Instructor: Contemporary Political Economy, Intermediate Macroeconomic Theory

2013 - 2014

Computer Science Department, Stanford University

Stanford, CA

Section Leader (Undergraduate TA, CS198 Program): Programming Methodologies, Programming Abstractions

2001 - 2002

Professional Experience _____

U.S. Department of State and U.S. Embassy in Iraq

Washington, DC and Baghdad, Iraq

INTERAGENCY TRANSITION ADVISOR/FOREIGN POLICY ADVISOR

- Served in the Bureau of Near Eastern Affairs in Washington and as State Dept advisor to the Deputy Commanding General of U.S. Forces-Iraq.
- Provided analysis of political developments, supported stabilization and interagency transition efforts to assist U.S. military departure.

POLITICAL-MILITARY AFFAIRS OFFICER

 Lead role in planning and implementing key political-military efforts for post-conflict transition in Iraq, including police development, nonproliferation compliance, election security, and militant group reconciliation, working with U.S., Iraqi Government and international partners.

WashingtonPost.com

Washington, DC 2007

EDITOR AND PRODUCER, POSTGLOBAL

· Coordinated, edited, and published expert panel blog, video blog, and interactive new media forum on foreign affairs.

STAFF REPORTER, WASHINGTON BUREAU

Washington, DC 2006 - 2007

• Covered the Pentagon, Senate and House Armed Services Committees, as a local reporter for a leading Japanese daily newspaper.

Skills

Asahi Shimbun

Programming: Python, R, C/C++, some Java

Languages: Proficient Spanish, intermediate German, beginning Arabic

Data Science: numpy, pandas, scipy, scikit-learn, statsmodels, matplotlib, spaCy, CoreNLP, SyntaxNet, Tensorflow, Git, Bash, AWS

APRIL 6, 2018 NATALIE AHN · RESUME

Papers & Presentations _____

INDUCING EVENT TYPES AND ROLES IN REVERSE: USING FUNCTION TO DISCOVER THEME.

2017. Proceedings of the Workshop on Events and Stories in the News, Association for Computational Linguistics (ACL)

COMPARING NLP METHODS FOR IDENTIFYING POLICY DECISIONS IN GOVERNMENT DOCUMENTS.

2017. Paper presented at the 2017 PoliInformatics Workshop

Rule-Based Spanish Morphological Analyzer Built From Spell Checking Lexicon.

2017. arXiv preprint, arXiv: 1707.07331 [cs.CL], code

MEASURING CONSOLIDATION OF POWER: EXTRACTING EVENT DATA FROM LAWS AND DECREES.

2016. Paper presented at the annual meeting of the American Political Science Association (APSA)

Fellowships & Awards_

Dissertation-Year Fellowship, Graduate Division, UC Berkeley, 2017-18

Outstanding Graduate Student Instructor Award, UC Berkeley, 2014

Humane Studies Fellowship, Institute of Humane Studies, 2013-15

Graduate Division Summer Grant, UC Berkeley, 2014

Faculty Summer Research Grant, UC Berkeley, 2013

Policy Fellowship, Nuclear Science and Security Consortium, 2012-13

Expeditionary Service Award, U.S. Department of State, 2011

Outstanding Civilian Service Award, U.S. Department of the Army, 2011

Institutional Affiliations

Visiting Researcher, Pontificia Universidad Católica del Perú (PUCP), Department of Social Sciences, Lima, Peru 2015

Associated Researcher, Facultad Latinoamericana de Ciencias Sociales (FLACSO), Dept of Political Studies, Quito, Ecuador 2016

Professional Activity

Reviewer for the Workshop on Natural Language Processing and Computational Social Science (NLP+CSS), ACL 2017

Reviewer for the International Conference on Computational Social Science (IC2S2) 2018

Member of the Association for Computational Linguistics, American Political Science Association, and Midwest Political Science Association